<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Gatekeeper</title>
    <link>https://gatekeeper.page/en/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Gatekeeper</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gatekeeper.page/en/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gatekeeper and password policies</title>
      <link>https://gatekeeper.page/en/blog/2021-gatekeeper-and-password-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Lukas Reschke</author>
      <guid>https://gatekeeper.page/en/blog/2021-gatekeeper-and-password-policies/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[ Most people probably have seen such an error message before when trying to change their password somewhere. And the usual reaction ends up just adding some special characters such as exclamation marks at the end of the password..]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[ <blockquote>
<p>&quot;Your password needs to contain a non-alphanumeric character and two upper-case characters.&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Most people probably have seen such an error message before when trying to change their password somewhere. And the usual reaction ends up just adding some special characters such as exclamation marks at the end of the password.</p>
<h1 id="the-story-behind-password-policies">The story behind password policies</h1>
<p>In 2004 the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) published a guideline for secure passwords in &quot;<a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/CSRC/media/Publications/sp/800-63/ver-10/archive/2004-06-30/documents/sp800-63-v1-0.pdf">Special Publication 800-63 Version 1.0</a>&quot;. Stating rules such as:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;composition rules that typically require users to select passwords that include lower case letters, upper case letters, and non-alphabetic symbols&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Ultimately, software vendors followed suit by adding absurd configuration flags inside their systems, allowing you to configure how many unique characters of which type are required. Enterprises saw this and now started demanding it from all possible vendors. If your software didn't support it, companies would just now buy from you.</p>
<p>Realistically, this didn't increase the security level of the system. Instead of &quot;password&quot;, people now would choose &quot;Password1!&quot;.</p>
<p>In 2017, NIST realized this and published &quot;<a href="https://pages.nist.gov/800-63-3/sp800-63b.html">800-63B</a>&quot;, moving away from recommendations of regular password changes and password composition requirements. They were instead advising towards checking against breached or weak passwords and a minimum password length.</p>
<h1 id="how-gatekeeper-uses-password-policies">How Gatekeeper uses password policies</h1>
<p>We believe in making software as easy to use as possible and coming with sane security defaults. There is barely any valid reason why organization A would require one more special character than organization B.</p>
<p>In terms of password checks, this means that Gatekeeper will come with a hard-coded password policy. There is no configuration required on your end, and Gatekeeper will automatically follow current best practices.</p>
<p>Gatekeeper will make users aware when their passwords are not deemed secure. Such as by being not long enough or having been breached earlier.</p>
<p><strong>User enters a too short password:</strong>
<img src="./password-not-long-enough.png" alt="Screenshot of Gatekeeper when a password is not long enough"></p>
<p><strong>User enters a breached password:</strong>
<img src="./password-not-unique-enough.png" alt="Screenshot of Gatekeeper when a password is not unique enough"></p>
<p><strong>User enters a secure password:</strong>
<img src="./password-ok.png" alt="Screenshot of Gatekeeper when a password is ok"></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User provisioning in 2020</title>
      <link>https://gatekeeper.page/en/blog/2020-user-provisioning-in-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Lukas Reschke</author>
      <guid>https://gatekeeper.page/en/blog/2020-user-provisioning-in-2020/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[ The lack of User Provisioning can cause Security and Privacy Risks, and you may not even be aware of them. Read on to understand the risks and how Gatekeeper can help mitigate them.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[ <p>User Provisioning seems to be one of these neglected topics. If you are a big enterprise, you probably care. But as a small and medium-sized enterprise or a regular home user? Why bother!</p>
<p>However, the lack of User Provisioning can cause Security and Privacy Risks, and you may not even be aware of them. Read on to understand the risks and how Gatekeeper can help mitigate them.</p>
<h1 id="manual-account-creation-is-risky">Manual account creation is risky.</h1>
<p>The days where it was possible to use a single-software to run your business are most likely over. Many companies rely on a lot of different systems for their business.</p>
<p>I've first hand seen many companies that create dedicated accounts for each employee on all their software systems. So everyone ends up with 5-10 different login credentials.</p>
<p>The lack of centralized user management causes several issues, such as:</p>
<p><strong>Account suspensions:</strong> You may forget to disable an account when an employee leaves the company. Failing to do so could result in data leaks and regulatory issues. (e.g., GDPR)</p>
<p><strong>Principle of least privilege:</strong> Users may move within teams and may not require access to previously used systems. Not handling such cases increases the overall risk footprint of your organization.</p>
<p><strong>Tipping off malicious actors:</strong> Imagine a hacker that took control of one of your user accounts. If you fail to disable access simultaneously, you may tip them off about their discovery.</p>
<h1 id="how-gatekeeper-secures-your-organization">How Gatekeeper secures your organization</h1>
<p>Gatekeeper supports several features that can instantly protect your organization.</p>
<p><a href="https://docs.gatekeeper.page/admin/managing-applications/understanding-settings/directory-modes/scim"><strong>SCIM:</strong></a> Gatekeeper will push any provisioning changes directly to any connected application. Your application will instantly be aware when a user has been deprovisioned.</p>
<p><a href="https://docs.gatekeeper.page/admin/managing-applications/understanding-settings/authentication-modes/gatekeeper-proxy"><strong>Gatekeeper Proxy:</strong></a> Gatekeeper will be acting as Reverse Proxy for all incoming traffic to your application and enforce authorization and authentication in real-time.</p>
<p><a href="https://docs.gatekeeper.page/admin/managing-applications/understanding-settings/directory-modes/ldap-directory"><strong>LDAP:</strong></a> Gatekeeper will be acting as an LDAP server. Your application can query user permissions on-demand.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Gatekeeper Documentation</title>
      <link>https://gatekeeper.page/en/blog/2020-introducing-the-gatekeeper-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Lukas Reschke</author>
      <guid>https://gatekeeper.page/en/blog/2020-introducing-the-gatekeeper-documentation/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[ We just published our first version of the Gatekeeper Documentation for administrators, users, and developers. Check it out at docs.gatekeeper.page.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[ <p>We just published our first version of the Gatekeeper Documentation for <a href="https://docs.gatekeeper.page/admin/">administrators</a>, <a href="https://docs.gatekeeper.page/user/">users</a>, and <a href="https://docs.gatekeeper.page/developer/">developers</a>. Check it out at <a href="https://docs.gatekeeper.page/">docs.gatekeeper.page</a>.</p>
<p><img src="./documentation-screenshot.png" alt="Screenshot of docs.gatekeeper.page"></p>
<h1 id="finding-the-right-documentation-software">Finding the right documentation software</h1>
<p>We had a few criteria for the right documentation software. Those being:</p>
<ol>
<li>Community members can contribute without hassles.</li>
<li>Data can be accessed using open formats.</li>
</ol>
<p>While we initially considered going with <a href="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/">Sphinx</a>, the experience isn&rsquo;t quite where we want it. Installing it isn&rsquo;t straight forward, and reStructuredText isn&rsquo;t intuitive to many people.</p>
<p>We ultimately settled on <a href="https://www.gitbook.com/">GitBook</a>. Despite it not being an open-source solution, it offers us the following advantages:</p>
<ul>
<li>Regular contributors can edit the documentation using the GitBook web UI.</li>
<li>Non-regular contributors can edit the documentation by making a Pull Request on GitHub.</li>
<li>GitBook provides hosting for us. And since we are an open-source project, this even <a href="https://www.gitbook.com/pricing">for free</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>As GitBook stores the data using Markdown in GitHub, there is also not much vendor lock-in. Any potential migration to other services in the future should thus be easily possible.</p>
<h1 id="helping-contributing">Helping contributing</h1>
<p>We&rsquo;d be happy for any contributions to our documentation. Just submit a Pull Request or Issue to our GitHub repositories, and we&rsquo;d happily incorporate your changes.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/GetGatekeeper/admin-documentation">GetGatekeeper/admin-documentation</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/GetGatekeeper/user-documentation">GetGatekeeper/user-documentation</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/GetGatekeeper/developer-documentation">GetGatekeeper/developer-documentation</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gatekeeper in a Snap</title>
      <link>https://gatekeeper.page/en/blog/2020-gatekeeper-in-a-snap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Lukas Reschke</author>
      <guid>https://gatekeeper.page/en/blog/2020-gatekeeper-in-a-snap/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[ As described in our earlier post: &ldquo;SaaS ate the world.&quot;. You don&rsquo;t need to bother with long installation processes, backups, let alone deploy updates timely. How can we get to a state in which on-premise software can compete with this?]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[ <p>As described in our earlier post: &quot;<a href="https://gatekeeper.page/en/blog/2020-why-is-there-a-need-for-gatekeeper/">SaaS ate the world.</a>&quot;. And one of the reasons for that is the fact that it is easy.</p>
<p>You don't need to bother with long installation processes, backups, let alone deploy updates timely. In the cloud, someone else is doing all this for you.</p>
<p>How can we get to a state in which on-premise software can compete with this?</p>
<h2 id="appliances-done-right-are-rare">Appliances done right are rare.</h2>
<p>Many software projects tend to offer appliances for download.</p>
<p>While this often allows for an easy installation, it doesn't solve the problem of updates. And that is what many appliances get wrong. They still require significant technical knowledge to be updated and maintained. (you get to update the operating system <strong>AND</strong> the software).</p>
<p>The sad reality is that many of these appliances get installed once and never updated. Not even for critical security vulnerabilities.</p>
<h2 id="meet-snaps">Meet Snaps</h2>
<p><a href="https://snapcraft.io/">Snaps</a> are containerized software packages. Compared to standard Linux packages (e.g., .deb), they are executed in a <a href="https://snapcraft.io/docs/security-sandboxing">sandbox</a> but have full control over the container.</p>
<p>Besides, Snaps are <a href="https://snapcraft.io/docs/keeping-snaps-up-to-date">automatically kept updated</a> and read-only by design. There's only a single folder that you need to update. And you don't have to take care of software updates at all.</p>
<p>Installing Snaps is also ridiculously easy. You have to run a single command. For example, to install Gatekeeper, all you have to do is run the following:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell">sudo snap install gatekeeper
</code></pre></div><p>And within less than a minute, you should have Gatekeeper installed and will automatically receive all security updates.</p>
<h2 id="how-does-this-all-work">How does this all work?</h2>
<p>In case you are interested how this all works, we have published <a href="https://github.com/getgatekeeper/gatekeeper-snap">our Snap package on GitHub</a>. In a nutshell, what it currently does is:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/GetGatekeeper/gatekeeper-snap/blob/cdde9398d38bbde07109cc0c745a414eec2321ad/snap/snapcraft.yaml#L2">Define Ubuntu 18.04 as base operating system</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/GetGatekeeper/gatekeeper-snap/blob/cdde9398d38bbde07109cc0c745a414eec2321ad/snap/snapcraft.yaml#L37-L57">Compile the frontend and backend of Gatekeeper</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/GetGatekeeper/gatekeeper-snap/blob/cdde9398d38bbde07109cc0c745a414eec2321ad/snap/snapcraft.yaml#L67-L83">Compile PostgreSQL</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/GetGatekeeper/gatekeeper-snap/blob/cdde9398d38bbde07109cc0c745a414eec2321ad/snap/snapcraft.yaml#L86-L98">Start PostgreSQL and Gatekeeper</a></li>
</ul>
<p>If we ever decide to add additional dependencies, you don't have to worry about this. Snap will take care of all that for you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is there a need for Gatekeeper?</title>
      <link>https://gatekeeper.page/en/blog/2020-why-is-there-a-need-for-gatekeeper/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Lukas Reschke</author>
      <guid>https://gatekeeper.page/en/blog/2020-why-is-there-a-need-for-gatekeeper/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[ I wrote down some of the reasons for the creation of the Gatekeeper project. Gatekeeper aims to be an open-source Identity Access Management solution, done in a way that anyone can run it.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[ <p>I wrote down some of the reasons for the creation of the Gatekeeper project. Gatekeeper aims to be an open-source <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Identity_management">Identity Access Management solution</a>, done in a way that anyone can run it.</p>
<h2 id="self-hosting-requires-it-knowledge">Self-hosting requires IT knowledge.</h2>
<p>In 2016 a friend of mine started a startup. They asked me for advice on what internal systems they should use for their company to keep their data away from the cloud.</p>
<p>As co-founder of <a href="https://nextcloud.com/">Nextcloud</a>, my initial advice was to give that a try for document management.</p>
<p>Shortly after, they asked me: &quot;What if we want to create email accounts, chat accounts, and more?&quot;</p>
<p>What should I have recommended them at this point? Nextcloud doesn't support all of these features, and they wanted a single login for all those features. And indeed, you can't teach everyone how to administrate an LDAP and SAML server.</p>
<p>So instead, they ended up using Google Apps for Business and Slack. From an end-user perspective, this is all great. Everything works with a few clicks.</p>
<p>It's December 2020, and instead of more open-source projects popping up to solve these problems, the opposite happened. SaaS ate the world.</p>
<h2 id="open-source-projects-lack-iam-support">Open-Source Projects lack IAM support.</h2>
<p>We ended up in a world where open-source projects often lack support for Identity Management systems. At the same time, proprietary and hosted software like <a href="https://slack.com/intl/en-uk/help/articles/212572638-Manage-members-with-SCIM-provisioning">Slack</a>, <a href="https://help.dropbox.com/accounts-billing/security/supported-identity-providers">Dropbox</a>, or <a href="https://www.workplace.com/resources/tech/account-management/automatic/">Facebook Workplace</a> supports these.</p>
<p>There are just a few open-source projects with official support for Identity Access Management (IAM) Systems. How did we end up with this state?</p>
<p>I believe the main reason boils down that there is no simple-to-use, easy-to-install open-source access management solution. There are many expensive Enterprise systems but barely do open-source maintainers have access to these.</p>
<p>The lack of such software leads to many downstream issues, such as the lack of high-quality open-source libraries for IAM support.</p>
<h2 id="how-does-gatekeeper-fix-this">How does Gatekeeper fix this?</h2>
<p>We can try to get to a state where more open-source projects will support IAM standards by creating an open-source Identity Access Management solution.</p>
<p>Gatekeeper aims to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Be easy to install and maintain.</li>
<li>Be secure by default.</li>
<li>Be easy to use.</li>
<li>Offer toolings and guidance for other software to implement IAM standards.</li>
</ul>
<p>Hopefully, that will lead to a world in which a button press will create users on all the software you desire to use. Be it on-premise or SaaS.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>