<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Gatekeeper</title>
    <link>https://gatekeeper.page/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Gatekeeper</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gatekeeper.page/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>User provisioning in 2020</title>
      <link>https://gatekeeper.page/en/blog/2020-user-provisioning-in-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gatekeeper.page/en/blog/2020-user-provisioning-in-2020/</guid>
      <description>The lack of User Provisioning can cause Security and Privacy Risks, and you may not even be aware of them. Read on to understand the risks and how Gatekeeper can help mitigate them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Gatekeeper Documentation</title>
      <link>https://gatekeeper.page/en/blog/2020-introducing-the-gatekeeper-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gatekeeper.page/en/blog/2020-introducing-the-gatekeeper-documentation/</guid>
      <description>We just published our first version of the Gatekeeper Documentation for administrators, users, and developers. Check it out at docs.gatekeeper.page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gatekeeper in a Snap</title>
      <link>https://gatekeeper.page/en/blog/2020-gatekeeper-in-a-snap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gatekeeper.page/en/blog/2020-gatekeeper-in-a-snap/</guid>
      <description>As described in our earlier post: &amp;ldquo;SaaS ate the world.&amp;quot;. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to bother with long installation processes, backups, let alone deploy updates timely. How can we get to a state in which on-premise software can compete with this?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is there a need for Gatekeeper?</title>
      <link>https://gatekeeper.page/en/blog/2020-why-is-there-a-need-for-gatekeeper/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gatekeeper.page/en/blog/2020-why-is-there-a-need-for-gatekeeper/</guid>
      <description>I wrote down some of the reasons for the creation of the Gatekeeper project. Gatekeeper aims to be an open-source Identity Access Management solution, done in a way that anyone can run it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Features</title>
      <link>https://gatekeeper.page/en/features/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gatekeeper.page/en/features/</guid>
      <description>Keep your user accounts safe and central.Self-hosted, secure and under your control. Gatekeeper gives you a centralized identity management under your control.
Central user management    Gatekeeper Directory Gatekeeper comes with a built-in user and group management.
      Easy setup  Gatekeeper is quick and easy to deploy, guiding you efficiently through the setup and avoiding unnessesary complications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Features</title>
      <link>https://gatekeeper.page/en/newsletter-subscribed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gatekeeper.page/en/newsletter-subscribed/</guid>
      <description>Successfully subscribed to the newsletter We will update you on all important news.
    You have an idea for a new feature? We always look forward to new feature ideas and to understand your use-cases.
 Submit my idea   Manage your users from one central place.    Gatekeeper Directory Gatekeeper comes with a built-in user and group management.
   Security Alerts Gatekeeper is built with security in mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get involved</title>
      <link>https://gatekeeper.page/en/community/contribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gatekeeper.page/en/community/contribute/</guid>
      <description>Help making Gatekeeper better!Gatekeeper is an open source project and developed collaboratively. Even if you&#39;re not a developer, you can get involved and make a difference.
   Community Chat  Help other Gatekeeper users and developers by joining our communication chat and answering questions.
Join the chat       Development  Contribute to Gatekeeper by fixing issues, improving functionality or implementing new features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install</title>
      <link>https://gatekeeper.page/en/install/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gatekeeper.page/en/install/</guid>
      <description>We are not quite ready yet...Gatekeeper is still under active development. We currently do not advise to run Gatekeeper in production as many of the features are not finished or hardened. If you&#39;re a developer and interested, you can however run the software locally.
Official installation methodsSnapAutomatic updates using Snap
SourceBuild from source yourself</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://gatekeeper.page/en/policy/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gatekeeper.page/en/policy/privacy/</guid>
      <description>Privacy Policy Last updated: January 1, 2021
This document covers the Privacy Policy of the Gatekeeper project (&amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo; / &amp;ldquo;us&amp;rdquo;). A personal project by Lukas Reschke.
If you have any questions about this privacy notice, please contact us at lukas@statuscode.ch.
What personal data do we collect? We collect data from two different sources. Either data you provide to us or data we collect automatically.
Provided by you Email address We may collect your email address for the following purposes:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>